<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reading on Lauren Pickings</title>
    <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on Lauren Pickings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 22:19:04 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neruaLLz.github.io/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>20241127</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2024/11/20241127/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 22:19:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2024/11/20241127/</guid>
      <description>晴天 深圳
这两天都是上午写了两封邮件，下午就在写文章和改文章，感觉快乐不少，这份工作又可以干下去了呢！
TIPS: 下次写文章的时候，确实是要先想好框架，也确实要不停问自己 so what，这样好像确实可以写得更顺畅一些。
逻辑通顺，上下文连接得好的时候，脑袋也确实会觉得好像通了一样。
Okay. Look no further. Next, I&amp;rsquo;ll review what I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt from the book Everybody writes so far. One of the most important principle for writing is clearity, brevity, and utility, which resonate with me. Then I have no idea what to write next. A few days ago, I saw an article on the Verge. It&amp;rsquo;s about the review of our competitors. It&amp;rsquo;s an thorough and honest review which contains negative and positive reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20241125</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2024/11/20241125/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 23:02:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2024/11/20241125/</guid>
      <description>阴天 深圳
早上出门上班的时候，很幸运，没有下雨。在路口转角处骑到了一辆小蓝车，一路慢悠悠地蹬到地铁站，居然只用了六分钟。AMAZING!
可能这也说明了 less is more, slow is fast 这一至尊道理吧。(θ‿θ)
今天的工作还是写邮件、发邮件，实在郁闷。不过其中一个客户倒是很有趣的。
他和伴侣结婚十余年，一起开了一家工作室。在一个宣传片中，他开玩笑道自己负责 run business，伴侣则负责 run his mouth。他们一个是时尚造型师，一个是室内设计师。一篇介绍他们的文章写道他们的设计风格是 it&amp;rsquo;s minimal, but warm。看了一些他们的设计成果图，我觉得也确实如此，很好看，可是我没有那么大的house。他们是同性恋伴侣，通过代孕的方式有了一个儿子，当了爸爸。
给他们写邮件的时候，我很自然就写下来了，不过还是让 AI 老师帮我润色了一下。但是，最后还是被改了。Take it easy.
今天中午下大雨，就在楼下吃了饭，吃了番茄咕噜肉、茄子、豆干、日本豆腐、米饭，感觉还不错呢。吃饭的时候忘记带耳机了，就看了一篇新闻。
确实，2024年11月11日晚发生在珠海体育中心旁边的全民健身广场的冲撞人群恶性事件，现在好像也已经淡出视野。逝者安息，不知道最后会不会有一个真相或者结果呢。
Today is just so-so.
英语输出好难呢，不过我要多写写，这样就会习惯的。✧٩(•́⌄•́๑)و ✧</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>面试问题汇总</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2024/06/%E9%9D%A2%E8%AF%95%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98%E6%B1%87%E6%80%BB/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 15:33:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2024/06/%E9%9D%A2%E8%AF%95%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98%E6%B1%87%E6%80%BB/</guid>
      <description>【英文内容策划】- hr 面试
自我介绍（中文） 19 年-22 年是全职备考吗？期间有参加全职工作吗？ 社会实践中的经历都是上学期间做的吗？ 这些经历都是线上参加的吗？ 因为读的是法律翻译专业，没有想过往法律方向发展吗？ 之前第一份工作为什么离职呢？ 所以第二份工作就更符合你希望从事的工作类型吗？ 为什么想参加考研呢？ 大学的时候读的英语专业，当时为什么选择英语专业呢？ 上一份实习是线下参与的吗？这份实习的体验怎么样呢？ 对于当老师感兴趣吗？ 这段时间有在找工作吗？找工作的历程是怎么样的呢？ 你更找哪方面的工作呢？有看到心仪的岗位吗？ 在读期间，有参加什么社团活动吗？ 有带领团队完成实践的经验吗？ 和同学一起完成的自媒体项目有取得什么成果吗？ 最近有在学习什么吗？ （回答有在学习关于写作的内容）平时有写作、写东西的习惯吗？ 平时喜欢看书吗？喜欢看什么类型的书？频率是怎么样的呢？ 还有什么其他爱好吗？ 有没有和小孩子一起看过英文绘本？ 感受：hr 面试会针对简历和相应的回答问得很细致，但是不太涉及到业务专业问题。我的回答需要更加简洁、有条理，说话应该更有力一些，不然感觉说着说着，很容易嘴瓢也。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note_of_Markdown</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2024/06/note_of_markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 16:26:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2024/06/note_of_markdown/</guid>
      <description>If you want to add an image in your markdown file, put the .md file and the image in the same directory, and then swrite the following syntax in .md file: To add a table in Markdown, use the vertical line | to separate each column, and use three or more dashes &amp;mdash; to create each column’s header. A vertical line should also be added at either end of the row.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20231030</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/10/20231030/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 23:21:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/10/20231030/</guid>
      <description>霾霾霾 北京
感觉自己像一个被焦虑和迷茫裹着的苦瓜人。面试没结果。
想静下心来写完论文，看完 LHL，学完 Python，练习翻译，入门游戏本地化，看很多想看的书，比如最近翻译的文章提到的《中国剩女》这本书。
但总是像鼓面一样，不停被焦虑鼓槌敲打。
打工人不想工作，没有工作的人急于找到工作。
看到今天的好运和牛奶有关，我早上就喝掉一瓶牛奶了，怎么好运还没来呢？难道要喝两瓶吗？那会长痘痘的。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 15:28:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/notes/</guid>
      <description>Loop: When you want to do the same action with every item in a list, you can use Python’s for loop. (p. 50)
Expected an indented block after &amp;lsquo;for&amp;rsquo; statement on line 3
Every indented line following the line for magician in magicians is considered inside the loop, and each indented line is executed once for each value in the list. (p. 52)
Any lines of code after the for loop that are not indented are executed once without repetition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20230904</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230904/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 16:14:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230904/</guid>
      <description>https://www.wired.com/story/poland-train-radio-attack-security-roundup/
https://techcrunch.com/2023/09/01/fbi-qakbot-takedown-operation-duck-hunt/
https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/29/fbi-operation-qakbot-uninstall/
https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/fujifilm-becomes-the-latest-victim-of-a-network-crippling-ransomware-attack/
https://www.justice.gov/usao-cdca/pr/qakbot-malware-disrupted-international-cyber-takedown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20230903</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230903/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 15:21:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230903/</guid>
      <description>第七条 劳动者有权依法参加和组织工会。
Article 7 Laborers shall have the right to participate in and organize trade unions in accordance with law.
工会代表和维护劳动者的合法权益，依法独立自主地开展活动。
Trade unions shall represent and safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of laborers, and stage activities independently in accordance with law.
第八条 劳动者依照法律规定，通过职工大会、职工代表大会或者其他形式，参与民主管理或者就保护劳动者合法权益与用人单位进行平等协商。
Article 8 Laborers shall take part in democratic management through workers congress, workers representative assembly, or any other forms in accordance with law, or consult with the employer on an equal footing about protection of the legitimate rights and interests of laborers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note 2</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/04/note-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 19:28:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/04/note-2/</guid>
      <description>SOURCE: https://www.science.org/content/article/alarmed-tech-leaders-call-ai-research-pause
Attracting signatures from the likes of Tesla CEO Elon Musk and Apple co-founder Steve Wozniak, the letter, released early last week, advocates for a 6-month moratorium to give AI companies and regulators time to formulate safeguards to protect society from potential risks of the technology.
AI has galloped along since the launch last year of the image generator DALL-E 2, from the Microsoft-backed company OpenAI.
The company has since released ChatGPT and GPT-4, two text-generating chatbots, to frenzied acclaim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note 1</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/02/note-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 22:12:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/02/note-1/</guid>
      <description>SOURCE: https://www.nytimes.com/2023/02/24/magazine/dating-prisoner-ethics.html
I have a childhood friend who recently moved into my home.
Although he still has 11 years left on his sentence, he is trying to appeal for a lesser term.
I am hopeful their relationship will end before he is released. Otherwise, I fear for her safety; I can see the red flags every day.
A separate issue is how you and your friends would feel if your roommate asked you to accept the presence of someone who caused all of you enormous distress, even if it was many years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
