<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>coursera--learning how to learn on Lauren Pickings</title>
    <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/tags/coursera--learning-how-to-learn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in coursera--learning how to learn on Lauren Pickings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 21:04:59 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neruaLLz.github.io/tags/coursera--learning-how-to-learn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>week3_Zombies_Everywhere</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/week3_zombies_everywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 21:04:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/week3_zombies_everywhere/</guid>
      <description>You can think of habits as having four parts, the first, is the cue. This is the trigger that launches you into zombie mode, the cue may be something as simple as seeing the first item in your to-do list. Time to start next week&amp;rsquo;s homework or seeing a text message from a friend, time to stop work.
A cue by itself is neither helpful or harmful. It&amp;rsquo;s the routine, what we do in reaction to that cue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week3_tackling_procrastination_it_is_easier_and_more_valuable_than_you_think</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/week3_tackling_procrastination_it_is_easier_and_more_valuable_than_you_think/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 20:58:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/week3_tackling_procrastination_it_is_easier_and_more_valuable_than_you_think/</guid>
      <description>The reason that learning to avoid procrastination is so important is that good learning is a bit by bit activity. You want to avoid cramming, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t build solid neural structures, by putting the same amount of time into your learning. But spacing that learning out by starting earlier, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn better.
First things first, unlike procrastination which is easy to fall into, willpower is hard to come by. It uses a lot of neural resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20230908</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230908/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 18:32:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230908/</guid>
      <description>Chunks are pieces of information, neuroscientifically speaking, that are bound together through use and often through meaning.
Chunks are best built with focused, undivided attention, understanding of the basic idea. And practice to help deepen your patterns and to help you gain big picture context.
Simple recall, trying to remember the key points without looking at the page, is one of the best ways to help the chunking process along. It seems to help build neural hooks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20230908</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230908/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 16:17:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230908/</guid>
      <description>When you&amp;rsquo;re learning a new idea, for example a new vocabulary word or a new concept or a new problem solving approach, you sometimes tend to practice it over and over again during the same study session. A little of this is useful and necessary, but continuing to study or practice after you&amp;rsquo;ve mastered what you can in the session is called overlearning.
Overleaning can have its place. It can produce an automaticity that can be important when you&amp;rsquo;re executing a serve in tennis or a perfect piano concerto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20230908</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230908/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 15:43:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230908/</guid>
      <description>The bigger and more well-practiced your chunked mental library, whatever the subject you&amp;rsquo;re learning, the more easily you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to solve problems and figure out solutions.
Chunking isn&amp;rsquo;t all you&amp;rsquo;ll need to develop creative flexibility in your learning, but it&amp;rsquo;s an important component. C
hunks can also help you understand new concepts. This is because when you grasp one chunk, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that that chunk can be related in surprising ways to similar chunks, not only in that field but also in very different fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20230906</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230906/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 23:10:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230906/</guid>
      <description>Neuromodulators are chemicals that influence how a neuron responds to other neurons, and today we will discuss three of them; acetylcholine, dopamine, and serotonin.
Acetylcholine neurons form neuromodulatory connections to the cortex that are particularly important for focused learning when you are paying close attention. These acetylcholine neurons project widely and activate circuits that control synaptic plasticity leading to new long term memory. Neuromodulators also have a profound impact on your unconscious mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20230906</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230906/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 20:17:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230906/</guid>
      <description>Hundreds of studies have shown that retrieval practice— retrieving the ideas from your own mind—is the best approach to learning. It not only builds memory but also significantly boosts your conceptual understanding.
What&amp;rsquo;s the best way to do retrieval practice? Use flashcards, repeating your practice over a number of days until you can retrieve the ideas, approaches, or techniques easily from your own mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20230905</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230905/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 19:48:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/20230905/</guid>
      <description>But psychologist, Jeffrey Karpicke, has shown that this approach is actually much less productive than another, very simple, technique. Recall. After you&amp;rsquo;ve read the material, simply look away, and see what you can recall from the material you&amp;rsquo;ve just read.
Students studied a scientific text and then practiced it, by recalling as much of the information as they could. Then they re-studied the text and recalled it again. That is, they tried to remember the key ideas, once more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WEEK2-How to From a Chunk-Part 2</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/week2-how-to-from-a-chunk-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 14:48:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/week2-how-to-from-a-chunk-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In this video, I&amp;rsquo;m going to walk you through the basic steps behind how to make a chunk.
Every discipline is a little different.
The first step on chunking is simply to focus your undivided attention on the information you want to chunk.
If you had the television going on in the background or you&amp;rsquo;re looking up every few minutes to check or answer your phone or computer messages, it means you&amp;rsquo;re going to have more difficulty in making a chunk, because your brain is not really focusing on chunking the new material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WEEK2-How to From a Chunk-Part 1</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/week2-how-to-from-a-chunk-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 14:32:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/week2-how-to-from-a-chunk-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Getting an initial sense of the pattern you want to master for yourself is similar for most subjects or skills.
The best chunks are the ones that are so well ingrained that you don&amp;rsquo;t even have to consciously think about connecting the neural pattern together.
That actually is the point of making complex ideas, movements or reactions into a single chunk.
You can see this in language learning.
In the beginning, often just saying a single word with the proper nuance, tone, and accent involves a lot of practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WEEK2-What is a Chunk</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/week2-what-is-a-chunk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 21:05:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/09/week2-what-is-a-chunk/</guid>
      <description>Just memorizing a fact without understanding or context doesn&amp;rsquo;t help you understand what&amp;rsquo;s really going on or how the concept fits together with other concepts you&amp;rsquo;re learning.
Notice there are no interlocking puzzle edges on the puzzle piece to help you fit it to other pieces.
Focusing your attention to connect parts of the brain to tie together ideas is an important part of the focused mode of learning. It is also often what helps get you started in creating a chunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20230830</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/08/20230830/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 14:41:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/08/20230830/</guid>
      <description>难翻的词及其译法：
struggle
Tell me about your own past struggles with writer&amp;rsquo;s block. 克服写作障碍
学到了 fiddle with your GPS
argument
That argument does not mesh with our everyday instincts.
这种观点并不符合我们的日常直觉。
incentive
It distorts incentives and pushes the allocation of scarce resources away from the optimum.
它扭曲了动机，使得稀缺资源的分配偏离理想状态。
Their incentive is to free ride on the general knowledge created by others.
他们希望免费利用其它人创造的知识。
so adj. that
The penalty for violating the decree is so large that no one dares try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20230823</title>
      <link>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/08/20230823/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 11:29:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neruaLLz.github.io/2023/08/20230823/</guid>
      <description>When you look at something that you really rather not do, it seems that you activate the areas of your brain associated with pain. Your brain, naturally enough, looks for a way to stop that negative stimulation by switching your attention to something else.
But here&amp;rsquo;s the trick. Researchers discovered that not long after people might start actually working out what they didn&amp;rsquo;t like, that neurodiscomfort disappeared. So it seems what happens when you procrastinate, is something like this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
